Criminal Justice, School of; Records ua640
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
School of Criminal Justice Records
1963-1988
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. School of Criminal Justice
ua640
14 cubic ft.
The files of the School of Criminal Justice consist primarily of records kept by Deans Richard Myren 1966-1976, and Donald Newman, 1977-84. They document the organization and formation of the School, particularly during the critical years of development (1963-1969).
Administrative History
The idea for a school of criminology was originally proposed by Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller during his first term as Governor (1958-1962), and on March 11, 1965, the SUNY Board of Trustees authorized the creation of the School of Criminal Justice [Proposal for the Program- Master of Science in Criminal Justice, September, 1966, p. 1]. The formation of the School was a "frank attempt to meet the current lack of meaningful research and educational programs relating to the criminal justice systems of the world" [Programs of the Ph. D. (Criminal Justice) and M.A. (Criminal Justice), February 1968, p. 2]. On June 15, 1966, Richard A. Myren was appointed as Dean of the School of Criminal Justice [Richard A. Myren, A Status Report, SUNYA School of Criminal Justice, November 1966, p. 2], and he was charged with the task of developing the graduate academic program of the School as well as with faculty recruitment.
In September of 1968, the first group of students was admitted to the newly formed School of Criminal Justice [Richard A. Myren, State University of New York at Albany, School of Criminal Justice, 1976, p. 27]. The two programs of the School were the M.A. and the Ph.D. in Criminal Justice, and in August 1971, the first Ph.D. from the School of Criminal Justice was awarded [Dean's Report, School of Criminal Justice, 1970-1971, p. 1]. In 1981 the Nelson A. Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy was formed, and the School of Criminal Justice became one of the four interdependent schools that comprise the college. In 1982, an undergraduate program (B.A.) in Criminal Justice was instituted [Programs and Priorities, Assessing a Decade, 1980-1990, p. 15].
In October of 1980, the Center on Minorities and Criminal Justice was founded to continue the activities of the Training Program in Criminal Justice in Education (established in 1977). Under the Directorship of Scott Christiansen, the goals of the Center were to continue the Minority Fellowship Program, and to conduct research relating to minorities and criminal justice. Due to a lack of continued funding, the Center was officially disbanded in January of 1982.
In 1985, the School of Criminal Justice was ranked as the top program in its field in the United States based on scholarly productivity and reputation [Criminal Justice Review, 10: 7-17, Fall 1985]. The School became affiliated with the Hindelang Criminal Justice Research Center, a leading center for the analysis and dissemination of criminal justice statistics information [Programs and Priorities, Assessing a Decade, 1980-1990, p.65].
Deans of the School of Criminal Justice
Richard Myren, 1966-1976
Vincent O'Leary, 1976-1977
Donald Newman, 1977-1984
Terence Thornberry, 1984-1987
David Duffee, 1987-1996
Scope and Contents
The files of the School of Criminal Justice consist primarily of records kept by Deans Richard Myren 1966-1976, and Donald Newman, 1977-1984. They document the organization and formation of the School, particularly during the critical years of development (1963-1969). Topics covered in the correspondence, faculty meeting minutes, Dean's Reports and planning documents primarily involve curriculum development and faculty recruitment. The correspondence demonstrates the involvement of Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller and the legal community in the formation of the School. The later documents reflect the day to day operations of the School of Criminal Justice, and the eventual absorption of the School into the Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy in 198?. This is evidenced through the daily correspondence, student handbooks, and school publications.
Also included are the records of the Schools' Center on Minorities and Criminal Justice, established in 1980 and directed by Scott Christiansen. The Center conducted research into areas of criminal justice such as the differential incarceration rate. The Center annotated and indexed scholarly literature relating to minorities and criminal justice in the Index to Minorities and Criminal Justice and also in various bibliographies compiled by members of the Center. Correspondence and publications document the development of those research activities of the Center on Minorities and Criminal Justice through its closure in 1982.
For records relating to the School of Criminal Justice, see also the personal papers of Deans Vincent O'Leary, Richard A. Myren, and Donald J. Newman, doctoral dissertations and masters essays.
A small number of photographs of students and staff from the School of Justice from the University Archives Photograph Collection are available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database.
Arrangement of the Collection
Divided into 5 file series.
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, by the School of Criminal Justice in February, 1992.
Access
Access to these records is unrestricted.
Criminal justice, Administration of -- Study and teaching -- New York (State).; Universities and colleges -- Graduate work.; Minutes.; Correspondence.; Manuals.; Administrative reports.; Publications.; Criminal Justice and Prisons; UAlbany Schools & Colleges; Myren, Richard A., 1924-; Newman, Donald J.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; State University of New York at Albany.; Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy.; State University of New York at Albany -- Curricula.
- Dean's Historical Day Files, 1963 April-1971 June; 1; 0.50 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  The historical day files of the Dean Richard Myren contain correspondence, faculty meeting minutes, planning and summary documents and general administrative documents generated during the years 1963-1971. The planning and organization of the School of Criminal Justice is well documented through memos and letters to the individuals directly involved in the creation of the program. For this series, the original item list compiled by the creating agency is intact, and there is an item level list of the files.
  Arrangement
  Arranged Chronologically.
  - Day Files, 1963 April-1963 December; 1.1
    - Extract from Current Biography, Vol. 24, No. 4, Lloyd E. Ohlin, 1963 April (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 1)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re Reorganization, Police Administration, Police Training, 04/09/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 2)
    - Memo to Lawrence Murray from Dean O.B. Conaway, re Center for Criminal Justice, 05/09/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 3)
    - Memo from Dean O.B. Conaway from Larry Murray, re Center for Criminal Justice, 05/15/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 4)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 05/28/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 5)
    - Letter to Eliot Lumbard from Frank Remington, 06/18/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 6)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re Administration of Criminal Justice, 06/19/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 7)
    - "A Law Science Center to Harness Advances of Science and Technology to the Law's Use", Newspaper clipping from New York Law Journal, Vol. 149, No. 122, 1964 June 25 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 8)
    - Letter to Prof. Frank J. Remington from E. Lumbard, 07/01/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 9)
    - Letter to Sol Corbin from Harry O'Donnell, 07/25/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 10)
    - Memo to Dr. T. Norman Hurd, Eliot Lumbard & Archibald Murray from Sol Corbin, 07/26/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 11)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re "THE ROCKEFELLER-REPUBLICAN RECORD", 08/07/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 12)
    - Letter to Dean O.B. Conaway from E. Lumbard, 08/27/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 13)
    - Letter to Frank Moore from Sol Corbin, 09/10/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 14)
    - A REPORT ON THE CORRECTIONS PROGRAM MADE TO THE CORRECTIONS ADVISORY COMMITTEE, by William P. Brown, GSPA, 09/10/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 15)
    - Letter to Professor Leon Radzinowicz from E. Lumbard, 09/18/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 16)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin & Eliot Lumbard from Frank Wille, re Administration of Criminal Justice, 09/26/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 17)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard, from Leon Radzinowicz, 09/28/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 18)
    - Letter to Frank C. Moore from Sol Corbin, 09/30/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 19)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re proposed 1964 program for the Administration of Criminal Justice, Undated (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 20)
    - Letter to Prof. Arthur Sherry from E. Lumbard, 10/01/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 21)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 10/01/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 22)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, 10/01/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 23)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re proposed 1964 program for the Administration of Criminal Justice, 10/01/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 24)
    - Letter to Milton Willner from E. Lumbard, 10/03/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 25)
    - Letter to Prof. Arthur Sherry from E. Lumbard, 11/18/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 26)
    - Letter to Eliot Lumbard from William Brown, 11/18/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 27)
    - NOTES AND ANNOUNCEMENTS - copy of article on School of Criminology (Berkeley), 11/19/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 28)
    - Memo to THE GOVERNOR from Sol Corbin, re 1964 Annual Message, 11/26/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 29)
    - "PREVENTION AND TREATMENT OF TODAY'S SOCIAL WELFARE PROBLEMS", Office of Legislative Research, 12/03/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 30)
    - Memo to Files from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 12/10/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 31)
    - Extract from Minutes of SUNY Trustee's Meeting, 1963 December 12 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 32)
    - Memo concerning message to Dr. Corbin from Mr. Murray of State University, 12/18/1963 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 33)
  - Day Files, 1964 January-1964 December; 1.2
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Dean O.B. Conaway, 01/07/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 34)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Message to the New York State Legislature, 01/08/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 35)
    - Letter to Dean W. David Curtiss from Christoph H. Schmidt, 02/07/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 36)
    - Press Release from Governor's Office, 02/27/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 37)
    - Press Release from Governor's Office, 03/02/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 38)
    - "NEW PROPOSALS AND CONTINUING ACCOMPLISHMENTS IN HIGHER EDUCATION IN NEW YORK STATE", Office of Legislative Research, 03/03/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 39)
    - Letter to Dean O.B. Conaway from E. Lumbard, 03/24/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 40)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 03/24/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 41)
    - Memo to Dean O.B. Conaway, Jr., from William P. Brown, re The Corrections Program - A Progress Report, 03/24/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 42)
    - Memo to Mr. J. Lawrence Murray from Dean O.B. Conaway, Jr. GSPA, re Establishment of a Center for Criminal Justice in State University of New York, 03/26/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 43)
    - "THE POLICE SCIENCE UNDERGRADUATE PROGRAM", from Gerald M. Leonard, Patrolman Planning Bureau, 04/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 44)
    - Press Release from Governor's Office, 04/03/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 45)
    - Memo on Meeting of Community College Representatives in Police Science, to O.B. Conaway from E. Lumbard, 04/21/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 46)
    - Press Release from Governor's Office, 04/24/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 47)
    - Listing of tentative candidates for Dean of SCJ, 05/04/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 48)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Charles S. Prigmore, 05/07/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 49)
    - "EXISTING CORRECTIONAL PLACEMENTS AND INTERNSHIPS IN NEW YORK STATE", Charles S. Prigmore, Ph.D., Educational Consultant for the Corrections, Undated (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 50)
    - Project, Council on Social Work Education, 05/11/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 51)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from O.B. Conaway, Jr., 05/11/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 52)
    - Memo to Files from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 06/04/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 53)
    - Letter to Eliot Lumbard from "Bill", Columbia University School of Law, 06/04/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 54)
    - Letter to U. of California from E. Lumbard, 06/05/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 55)
    - Letter to Lawrence Murray from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 56)
    - Letter to Frank Moore from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 57)
    - Letter to Eliot Lumbard from Frank Moore, 07/01/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 58)
    - Clipping from The New York Times, - Paul W. Tappan, Educator, Dead, Professor of Criminology and Law at Berkeley, 52, 07/10/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 59)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 07/14/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 60)
    - Letter to Mr. Lester B. Granger from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 08/11/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 61)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Frank Remington, 08/24/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 62)
    - Press Release from Governor's Office, letter of welcome to President Gould, 08/31/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 63)
    - Copy "Hoover Seeks Pay increases for Law Enforcers Sees Lack of Funds Responsible for Crime Growth", New York Law Journal, 09/02/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 64)
    - Graduate School of Public Affairs, "PROPOSAL TO INSTITUTE A NEW MAP PROGRAM", by William P. Brown, 09/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 65)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re SCJ, 09/15/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 66)
    - Letter to Mr. J. Lawrence Murray from O.B. Conaway, Jr., 09/18/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 67)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, 10/06/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 68)
      re School of Criminal Justice.
    - Listing of students, 10/27/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 69)
    - Copy of letter to Dr. Lloyd E. Ohlin from Samuel B. Gould, 11/12/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 70)
    - Letter to Eliot Lumbard from Harry W. Porter, 11/13/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 71)
    - State University of New York, "THE MASTER PLAN", Undated (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 72)
    - Excerpts from "The Legislature and Higher Education in New York State", a report by the Legislature's Consultant on Higher Education, 12/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 73)
    - Press Release from Governor's Office, re Master Plan, 12/09/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 74)
  - Day Files, 1964 December-1965 June; 1.3
    - Copy of The New York Times article, "Crime Institute in City Proposed, Ford Fund urged to Finance Independent Agency", by Paul Crowell, 12/27/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 75)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Orrell A. York, special program for Police Administrators for the 1965 Institute, 12/28/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 76)
    - Letter to Alexander Aldrich from E. Lumbard, 12/30/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 77)
    - Letter to Dr. Harry Porter from E. Lumbard, 12/30/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 78)
    - The Police Academy Publication, 01/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 79)
    - Letter to Dr. Samuel B. Gould from E. Lumbard, 01/04/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 80)
    - "THE ROLE OF CRIMINOLOGY AND A PROPOSAL FOR AN INSTITUTE OF CRIMINOLOGY", report by Prof. Leon Radzinowicz, 01/07/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 81)
    - Press Release from Police Department, City of New York, re Remarks of Police Commissioner Michael J. Murphy, 01/10/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 82)
    - Press Release from Police Department, City of New York, re special training course, 01/10/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 83)
    - Letter to Prof. L. Radzinowicz from E. Lumbard, 01/13/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 84)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Leonard E. Reisman, re Forum "The Citizen and the Policeman: Review Boards and Other Procedures", 02/02/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 85)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Leon Radzinowicz, 02/22/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 86)
    - Memo to Dr. Gould from E. Lumbard, re speech by Dr. Glueck, 02/28/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 87)
    - Letter to Lloyd Ohlin from E. Lumbard, 03/02/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 88)
    - Letter to Prof. Leon Radzinowicz from E. Lumbard, 03/02/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 89)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from L. Radzinowicz, 03/09/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 90)
    - Board minutes, 03/11/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 91)
    - Letter to Eliot Lumbard from Lloyd Ohlin, 03/15/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 92)
    - Memo to Samuel Gould from Lloyd Ohlin, re Report on the Establishment of a School of Criminology and Criminal Justice by the State University of New York, 04/1964 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 93)
    - Draft Press Release, 04/06/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 94)
    - Draft Press Release, re SCJ being organized in the State University of New York, 04/07/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 95)
    - Memo to Judge Breitel from E. Lumbard, 04/08/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 96)
    - Press Release from Governor Rockefeller, 04/13/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 97)
    - Letter to L. Ohlin from E. Lumbard, 04/19/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 98)
    - Newspaper clipping "Our 40, 000 Police Forces" by Ruth Montgomery - to E. Lumbard from Orrell York, 04/22/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 99)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re May 27 meeting, 04/29/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 100)
    - Memo to Eliot Lumbard from Sol Corbin, re May 27 meeting, SCJ, 04/29/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 101)
    - Letter to Lloyd Ohlin from E. Lumbard, 05/05/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 102)
    - Letter to Harry Porter from E. Lumbard, 05/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 103)
    - Letter to Frank C. Moore from E. Lumbard, 05/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 104)
    - Letter to Dr. Samuel B. Gould from E. Lumbard, 05/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 105)
    - Letter to Charles D. Breitel from E. Lumbard, 05/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 106)
    - Letter to Prof. Herbert Wechsler from E. Lumbard re dinner meeting, 05/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 107)
    - Letter to Samuel Rosenman from E. Lumbard, 05/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 108)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re May 27th meeting SCJ, 05/19/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 109)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Frank Moore, 05/20/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 110)
    - Letter to E. Lumbard from Samuel Rosenman re dinner meeting, 05/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 111)
    - Letter to Mr. Clifton Daniel from E. Lumbard, 06/01/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 112)
    - Letter to Miss Charlotte Harlander from James D. Bateman, 06/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 113)
    - Letter to Prof. Leon Radzinowicz from E. Lumbard, re Ohlin's "Report on the Establishment of a School of Criminology and Criminal Justice by the State University of New York", 06/23/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 114)
  - Day Files, 1965 June-1966 July; 1.4
    - A SHORT HISTORY OF THE ALBANY GRADUATE PROGRAM IN PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 115)
    - Letter to Dr. Harry Porter from Eliot Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 116)
    - Letter to Judge C. Breitel from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 117)
    - Letter to Prof. Herbert Wechsler from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 118)
    - Letter to Dr. Harry Porter from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 119)
    - Letter to Samuel B. Gould from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 120)
    - Memo to Sol Corbin from E. Lumbard, re SCJ Meeting, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 121)
    - Letter to Samuel I. Rosenman from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 122)
    - Letter to Frank C. Moore from Eliot Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 123)
    - Letter to Clifton Phalen from E. Lumbard, 06/24/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 124)
    - Letter to Eliot Lumbard from Charles D. Breitel, 06/28/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 125)
    - Memo to Dean O.B. Conaway, Jr., to Prof. William Brown, 07/06/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 126)
      re The Ohlin Report of April 1965.
    - Article - "Wanted: A New Legal Profession", by Professor Sheldon Glueck, Undated (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 127)
    - Letter to Dr. Samuel Gould from E. Lumbard, 08/18/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 128)
    - Letter to Dr. Harry Porter from E. Lumbard, 08/21/1965 (Box 1 (1-Dean's Historical Day Files), Folder 129)